Their affair ignited a scandal. Their passion brought down an empire.
W.E. is a drama, romance film directed by Madonna.
In 1998, an auction of the estate of the Duke and
Duchess of Windsor causes great excitement.
For one woman, Wally Winthrop, it has much more meaning.
Wally becomes obsessed by their historic love story.
As she learns more about the sacrifices involved, Wally
gains her own courage to find happiness.
Wally Winthrop, played by Abbie Cornish.
Wallis Simpson, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Edward, played by James D'Arcy.
Evgeni, played by Oscar Isaac.
William Winthrop, played by Richard Coyle.
Ernest, played by David Harbour.
(stylised W./E.) is a 2011 historical romantic drama film written and directed by Madonna and
starring Abbie Cornish, Andrea Riseborough, Oscar Isaac, Richard Coyle, and James D'Arcy.
The screenplay was co-written by Alek Keshishian, who previously worked with Madonna
on her 1991 documentary Truth or Dare and two of her music videos.
Although the film was panned by critics and was a box office bomb, it
received an Academy Award nomination for Best Costume Design.
This marked Isaac's and Cornish's second film together after Sucker Punch.
The film tells the story of two women separated by over six decades.
In 1998, lonely New Yorker Wally Winthrop is obsessed with Edward VIII's abdication
of the British throne so he could marry American Wallis Simpson.
But Wally's research, including several visits to Sotheby's auction of the Windsor estate,
reveals that the couple's life together was not as perfect as she thought.
Traveling back and forth in time, W.E.
intertwines Wally's journey of discovery in New York with the story of Wallis and Edward from the
early days of their romance to the unraveling of their lives over the following decades.
The film explores themes of auction, beating, bathtub, clothes, woman director.
The tone is emotional.